MISSION 22 "IT'S JUST THE POOL."
（任务22 游泳池）
POOL DAY
（去游泳池的日子）
ALL READY
（准备齐全）
CHECKS HER BAG AGAIN
（再检查一次携带物品）
ALMOST TIME TO GO. GETTING NERVOUS.
（快到约好的时间 开始紧张不安）
CHECKS HER BAG FOR THE SEVENTH TIME
（第七次检查携带物品）
Shoko!
硝子！
Isn't it nearly time to go?
差不多该出门了吧？
CLOCK
（时钟）
Have you got everything?
有没有忘记带什么？
Towel? Wallet?
浴巾带了没？钱包带了没？
Bathing suit? Goggles? Tissues?
泳衣带了没？ 泳镜带了没？纸巾带了没？
-NO TIME FOR THAT! -Handkerchief? Bug spray? Coin purse?
-（没时间确认那些事） -手帕、防蚊液、零钱包带了没？
YOMIKIRI LAND STATION
（读切乐园站）
30 MINUTES EARLY
（古见同学还是早到了30分钟）
When a person has extreme social anxiety…
所谓的“交流障碍症” 是指不擅长和人交流的一种症状
10 MINUTES LATER
（10分钟后）
…they struggle to communicate with others.
或是指有这种症状的人
GETTING NERVOUS
（开始紧张了）
Bear in mind…
不过需要注意的是…
Hey!
嗨！
Sorry you had to wait and long time no see!
久等了 好久不见！
You're so early, Komi!
古见同学 你来得好早！
Oh, that's the dress Tadano picked.
这是只野同学帮你选的那件连衣裙吧
Love it. It looks great!
不错 你穿起来很好看！
Let's get going!
那我们走吧！
Um, uh…
啊 那个…
You look very nice.
你穿起来很好看
Bear in mind…
不过需要注意的是…
What are you doing?
你们在干什么？
I'll leave you behind!
我要丢下你们了！
Okay, okay.
好 来了
…they only struggle to form connections.
这些人只是不擅长社交
It doesn't mean that they don't want to.
但并不表示他们不想和别人有往来
This is going to be great!
哇 好期待呀
I wonder if there'll be any nip-slip action.
穿泳装会出现走光画面吗？
What are you saying?
你在说什么鬼话？
W-Wait up!
等等我啊！
Don't leave me behind!
请不要丢下我啊！
Oh, I forgot I invited Agari.
啊 我都忘记邀请过上理了
You're terrible.
你太过分了吧
Wait!
等一下！
Don't leave us behind!
不要丢下我们！
I didn't invite Yamai and the gang.
我并没有找山井他们啊
Oh my, if it isn't Komi! What a coincidence.
天啊 这不是古见同学吗？好巧哦
We've all come to the pool too.
我们大家刚好也想来游泳池
D-Deja vu…
这场面似曾相识
Hey, I know!
啊 对了！
Since we're all here, let's go together!
难得这么碰巧 干脆我们两组人并为一组
We can hang out!
大家一起去玩吧！
Yeah! Let's do that!
真棒 就这么办！
Fine with me but how about you Komi?
我是没意见 但古见同学呢？
N… NOD…
（点头）
MORE PEOPLE MEANS MORE STRESS.
（人数增加 令她更加紧张）
Summer!
夏日！
Sun!
阳光！
Pool!
游泳池！
Woo! Yay!
哇！耶！
Let's do this!
好耶！
Hey you guys.
你们几个
Don't get too rowdy in front of Komi.
不准在古见同学面前太过喧闹
Got it.
是
Let's go!
那我们走吧！
See ya, Tadano.
只野同学 待会儿见
Bye.
好
Hang on, where are you going?
慢着 你要去哪边？
-Huh? -Don't give me that.
-什么？ -不要装傻
The moment I've been waiting for!
终于让我等到这一刻
Eight days after the summer holidays have started…
进入暑假后的这八天
It was worth staking out Komi's house every day!
我每天守在古见同学家门口 果然是值得的！
Komi getting changed! Komi's skin!
古见同学换衣服！ 古见同学的肌肤！
Komi's bathing suit!
古见同学的泳装！
What does Komi have in store for…
来吧 古见同学 会让我看到怎样的泳装…
SCHOOL BATHING SUIT
（学校制式泳衣）
H-Her school bathing suit?
居然是学校制式泳衣？
Komi, don't you have any other bathing suit?
古见同学没有一般的泳衣吗？
Even so, Komi in a school suit…
可是古见同学穿学校泳衣的模样…
I want to see it! I want to see, but…
想看！我好想看！可是…
Komi, let's go buy a bathing suit.
古见同学 我们先去买泳衣吧
Yamai doesn't want the gang to see Komi's dorky side.
山井同学不想让众人看到 古见同学的重口味装扮
Thanks for waiting!
让你们久等了！
It's so hot out.
哇 好热啊
CHANGED IN THE UNIVERSAL RESTROOM
（结果在男女兼用的洗手间更衣）
Ten points.
十分
S-Sorry for the wait!
不好意思让各位久等了！
It took me a while to get into my suit.
穿泳衣花了我很多时间
-Ten points.
-十分
Ten points.
十分
It's so crowded.
人果然好多
Did you get a spot for us?
你们先去帮忙占位子了吗？
Ten points.
十分
Wow!
天啊！
-100 million points.
-一亿分！
100 million points.
一亿分！
100 million points?
一亿分？
First off…
首先…
The waterslides!
来玩滑水道！
Yay!
耶！
Oh, they're two-seaters.
是两人一组呢
Hey Agari, let's go together!
上理 跟我一组吧！
Y-You really want to go with me?
你要选我吗？
Yeah. You'll be a good cushion if anything goes wrong.
是啊 万一出事了 你还可以当缓冲垫
Komi, come with me!
古见同学 跟我一组吧！
-No, me! -Let's go together!
-不 跟我吧！ -我们一起来滑！
Rock, paper, scissors!
剪刀、石头、布！
Shoot! Shoot! Shoot!
再来一次！
Excuse me.
不好意思
You'll do. Just hurry up.
就你去吧 动作快点
Uh, alright. Pardon me.
那真是不好意思
RUMBLE
（发怒）
I don't hate this.
这样也别有一番乐趣呢
Tadano discovered a new thrill.
只野同学点燃了新的嗜好
A-Are you alright?
你还好吗？
WANTS TO GO AGAIN.
（还想再玩一次）
Shall we go again?
要再玩一次吗？
KOMI WENT FOUR MORE TIMES.
（古见同学在那之后又滑了四次）
Let's go to the lazy river!
接下来去漂漂河吧！
Hooray!
好好玩！
Woof! Woof, woof, woof!
汪！
YAMAI AND THE GANG
（山井同学一行人）
Something's in the water.
水里好像有东西
Let's see who can hold their breath longest!
来比赛 看谁憋气能憋最久！
The first one up buys the winner a soda.
最后一名要请第一名喝果汁
-Ready? Go! -Hang on!
-那就准备 开始！ -等等！
KOMI GOT NINE CANS OF SODA.
（古见同学获得九罐饮料）
Hey, Komi, um…
古见同学 那个…
Oh, it's nothing.
不 没事
Whew.
天啊
This sure is fun.
真是太好玩了
Wow!
哦！
Alright! To the diving board next!
好 接下来去跳水台！
Running is dangerou…
用跑的很危险…
Komi!
古见同学！
TRIP
（摔倒）
Komi! Augh!
古见同学 呜！
Komi!
古见同学！
FIRST AID STATION
（医护室）
Komi, are you alright?
古见同学 你还好吗？
NOD…
（点头）
Wow, talk about bad vibes.
天啊 现在气氛好尴尬
You can't go in the pool now with that scrape.
既然受伤就没办法下水了
We've had enough fun. Let's go home.
反正也玩够了 我们就回去吧
Y-Yes!
好！
I agree.
也对啦
SHAKE SHAKE
（摇头）
-FRET -NOTHING TO WRITE WITH!
（四处寻找 没有纸跟笔 无法写字）
I'll bring it.
我去拿
DON'T WORRY ABOUT ME. GO HAVE FUN.
（大家不用在意我 继续玩吧）
B-But…
可是…
Alright!
好！
Okay, let's all go to the lazy river again!
那我们再去玩一次漂漂河！
Hey, hang on.
喂 你这样不好吧
-Let's go, everyone! -Hey, wait.
-好了 我们走吧！ -等一下！
You too, Yamai!
山井也来！
Um, no, I'm…
不 我还是…
Komi, you stay with our bags and rest!
古见同学 你在我们放行李的地方休息吧！
NOD
（点头）
Najimi, hang on. I…
驯染 等一下 我还是…
Times like this, it's best to have fun and not fuss.
这种时候要照样开心玩 不顾虑她才是最好的方法
Otherwise she'll think it's her fault for ruining our good time.
不然古见同学会认为 是自己破坏了大家的兴致
Komi will feel bad, right?
这样会让她内疚的 对吧？
You've learned how to read the room.
你居然会察言观色了
Huh? You mean I haven't always been reading it?
等等 我以前都没有察言观色吗？
That's not the issue.
我不是那个意思
I'm going to file down that bad poolside.
我是想说去锉一锉 那个害古见同学受伤的泳池边
I wanted to say that's why I'm not going.
所以没办法跟大家一起去玩
Where to next?
接下来去玩什么？
Does it still hurt?
你还痛吗？
Oh, sorry I startled you.
对不起 吓到你了
DIDN'T YOU GO TO THE LAZY RIVER?
（你不是去玩了吗？）
Oh, I'm tired so I decided to take a break.
没有啦 我有点累了 想休息一下
It's alright.
没事的
Najimi and Agari are having fun.
驯染她们玩得很开心
Yamai and the gang are filing down the spot where you tripped.
山井同学他们正在 锉让你摔倒的泳池边
Yeah, I don't really get it either,
其实我也觉得莫名其妙
but your friends are all good people, Komi.
你的朋友都是一群好人
You don't have to worry that they'll hate you.
你不用担心他们会讨厌你
I HAD FUN.
（我玩得很开心）
IT WAS SO FUN BEING IN THE POOL WITH EVERYONE.
（跟大家在游泳池玩耍非常开心）
BUT I RUINED EVERYONE'S GOOD TIME…
（却因为我的关系 让大家不开心）
I HATE THIS FEELING.
（我讨厌我自己）
Komi!
古见同学！
If you look sad, nobody will be able to have a good time.
看到你一脸难过的样子 大家肯定开心不起来！
Can you stand?
站得起来吗？
-Komi's hand! Oh, never mind! -NOTICED HE WAS HOLDING HER HAND.
-古见同学的手！没事！ -（这瞬间注意到自已牵着她的手）
Komi-- blublublub…
古见同学 噗…
Hey, hey!
你们两个！
Enough with the teenage drama!
以为在拍青春偶像剧吗？
We bought these so you can play too, Komi.
我买了这个来 这样古见同学也能一起玩了
H-Here! Use this water gun!
请用这把水枪！
We'll join you!
我们也要加入！
Hey!
来吧！
-Eat this! -Naji-- blublublub…
-看招！ -驯…噗
Whew.
话说回来
I didn't expect you to go flying into the lifeguard.
想不到你会对救生员 使出头部滑垒这一招
Classic Tadano.
不愧是只野同学
Shut up.
别再说了
Agari, did you have a nip-slip?
上理没有走光吧？
Huh? Uh…
什么？啊…
The waterslides were so fun.
滑水道好好玩
Yeah, I know, right?
就是啊
It was a good day, hey Tadano?
今天玩得很开心吧？只野同学
Hm?
嗯？
Yeah.
是啊
It was fun.
很开心
Komi's shoulder. Ah ha ha.
古见同学的肩膀 哈…
MISSION 23 "IT'S JUST SHAVED ICE."
（任务23 刨冰）
Hm? What?
你说什么？
Going to the library?
你要去图书馆吗？
Alone?
一个人去？
SCARED
（害怕）
My, isn't that unusual.
好难得啊
Alright, take care.
那路上小心
CICADA
（蝉）
Will you be okay?
你这样没问题吗？
Honey.
老公
Shoko's going to the library.
硝子说她要去图书馆呢
HE'LL WALK HER THERE.
（决定由爸爸送她过去）
I never know how you two communicate.
还是老样子 不晓得你们是怎么沟通的
SHAVED ICE
（刨冰）
Welcome.
欢迎光临
-How lovely! -What a handsome man.
-好帅！ -好绅士的大叔！
What a beautiful girl!
超级美少女！
Why don't they talk?
他们怎么都不说话？
Are they fighting?
是在吵架吗？
Having a serious discussion?
是要讨论什么严肃话题吗？
What can I get you?
决定要点什么了吗？
GREEN TEA AND SWEET BEAN
（宇治金时冰）
-STRAWBERRY MILK -Coming right up.
-（草莓牛奶冰） -好的
-LOOKING FORWARD TO SHAVED ICE -WANTS TO ASK ABOUT HIGH SCHOOL
（想问女儿学校生活如何 期待着草莓牛奶冰）
-WHERE IS IT? -COMING HERE WAS JUST AN EXCUSE TO ASK.
（邀女儿吃冰就是为了问这个 还没好吗？）
Thank you for waiting.
两位久等了
-IT'S HERE! -COULDN'T ASK…
（但还是问不出口！ 来了！）
BRAIN FREEZE
（凉到头痛）
How's school?
学校生活如何？
I SAID IT!
（问出口了！）
GLOOM
（表情灰暗）
SMILE
（没事的表情）
SHE WAS JUST KIDDING.
（开玩笑的）
BRAIN FREEZE
（凉到头痛）
HAPPY
（开心）
MISSION 24 "IT'S JUST A LIBRARY."
（任务24 图书馆）
MATTAN MUNICIPAL LIBRARY
（松旦市立图书馆）
NICE AND COOL
（凉爽）
FOUND A NEAT BOOK
（发现有趣的书）
THE GROVE OF GOATS AND IRON
（《羊与铁之森》）
-BEAUTIFUL… -PRECIOUS…
（美少女 好尊贵）
-OH MY… -PRETTY…
（天啊 好美啊）
KOMI RUNS TO THE CHECKOUT DESK.
（古见同学如逃跑般跑去借书）
Thank you for the return.
您好 还书是吗？
Please come again.
欢迎再次光临
Oh.
啊
LOITER
（徘徊）
CAN'T TAKE THAT FINAL STEP
（就是踏不出那一步）
READS HER BOOK TO CALM HER NERVES
（古见同学决定先读书镇定一下）
Ko, what's wrong? Are you hungry?
小光 怎么了？肚子饿了吗？
Oh, you stopped crying.
啊 不哭了
That's a good boy, Ko.
要当个乖宝宝哦 小光
TRYING TO SMILE KINDLY
（自认为笑得很温柔）
SHIVER
（颤抖）
Ko?
小光？
What's wrong, Ko?
小光 怎么了？
KOMI PANICS
（吓到宝宝令她惊慌失措）
Ko?
小光？
I wonder what that was about?
刚刚到底是怎么了？
PHEW
（松了一口气）
TADANO CAME TO RETURN SOME BOOKS.
（刚好来图书馆还书的只野同学）
I witnessed a precious moment.
看到了宝贵的一幕
He forgot to return the books.
他忘记还书了
MISSION 25 "IT'S JUST A PARK."
（任务25 公园）
THIS IS FUN!
（开心！）
KOMI GOES AGAIN.
（古见同学要再玩一次）
HIGHER THAN EXPECTED. KOMI GETS SCARED.
（意外地比想象的还高 古见同学开始害怕）
CLOUD HANDS
（云手）
TADANO HEADS BACK THE LIBRARY TO RETURN THE BOOKS.
（再次回图书馆还书的只野同学）
I witnessed a precious moment.
看到了宝贵的一幕
And he forgot to return the books.
然后他又忘了还书
Subtitle translation by:
字幕翻译：薛卓